JAMES HELLINGER

503-748-9952 | Hillsboro, OR | james.heilinger@gmail.com | <u>www.linkedin.com/in/james-heilinger</u>

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

I am a driven individual seeking a remote position as a software developer using my skills as a computer programmer and my passion for learning mobile app design and web technologies.

- 6+ years' experience working in software development.
- Comfortable following the Agile process; familiar with using JIRA for story tracking.
- Range of experience from Python and UI development to DevOps and software testing.
- Excellent written and verbal communication skills.
- Proven track record learning required technical skills to perform my job duties.

EXPERIENCE

Intel Corporation, Hillsboro, OR

April 2012 – November 2020

Software Development Engineer, April 2014 – November 2020

Responsible for writing and maintaining conformance test automation scripts, Jenkins CI/CD infrastructure and pipelines, and creating tests for the team's products.

- Identified pain points in maintaining the team's Jenkins infrastructure and initiated fixing them by converting to Pipeline jobs, reducing the number of jobs needed and work required to maintain them.
- Leveraged features of our Qt-based UI framework and put in place a process allowing the team to automatically generate tests for our software.
- Designed a graphical UI tool using pure JavaScript, HTML and CSS to assist the developers in creating the object names required for the automatic test generator, saving valuable developer time.
- Created a flexible and extendable Python based hardware simulator to test the team's graphical hardware debug tool.
- Wrote Python scripts used for electrical conformance testing, interfacing with multiple pieces of test
 equipment, the hardware under test and data processing software. Python best practices and
 coding standards were followed.

Network Hardware Engineer, April 2012 – April 2014

Responsible for debugging customer issues related to 1G Ethernet server cards, testing LAN magnetics, and developing conformance test automation scripts.

- Trained across geographic barriers to facilitate conformance test station setup with our counterpart lab in Asia.
- Collaborated with an Intel group in California to test the SFP+ electrical conformance of the switch platform they were designing.
- Leadership role in testing 1G LAN magnetics modules. This required me to draft a clear test plan, communicate with several departments, and influence vendors to test larger quantities for us.

Portland General Electric Company, Portland, OR

June 2011 – February 2012

Undergraduate intern

Responsible for performing transmission system study work for generation interconnection requests and transmission planning projects.

• Performed study work on the Portland, Oregon, and surrounding area transmission system for generation interconnection requests.

- Created a generic PowerWorld model for wind farms following the WECC generic wind farm modeling guidelines.
- The company valued my contributions and extended the 6-month internship another 3 months part-time while I completed my degree.

Intel Corporation, Hillsboro, OR

April 2010 – March 2011

Undergraduate intern

Responsible for assisting with LAN magnetics module testing, test procedure updates and post-processing test data.

- Tested LAN magnetics transformer modules to collaborate with vendors and improve performance.
- Created a script to post-process data for vendor meetings.
- Learned to operate 2-, 4-, and 16-port VNAs, Time Domain Reflectometers (TDR), and LCR meters.
- The group was impressed with my work and extended the 6-month full-time internship another 6 months part-time while I took classes full-time.

EDUCATION

Portland State University, Portland, OR Bachelor of Science (B.S.), Electrical Engineering, cum laude. Power Systems emphasis.

ACCOMPLISHMENTS AND GROWTH

- Competed in a company sponsored secure code challenge event where I learned the basics of fixing security vulnerabilities for web applications. Vulnerabilities included SQL injection attacks, reflected cross-site scripting, bad authentication schemes, insecure data storage and many more. I placed 17th out of 215 participants.
- Completed several tutorials in my spare time to gain experience in full-stack web development, including front-end design with React and Angular and back-end Restful API design with Express, MongoDB, and Node.js.
- Designed a wireless home security alarm using Arduino, building a custom software package for it.